<!DOCTYPE html>
<html>
	<head>
		<meta name="viewport" content="initial-scale=1.0, user-scalable=no" />
		<meta charset='utf-8' /> 
		<title>gamelab</title>
		<link href="https://maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.3.0/css/font-awesome.min.css" rel="stylesheet" />
		<link rel="stylesheet" href="index.css" type="text/css" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<header>
			<div>
				<span>Version @VERSION@</span>
				<a href="#"><i class="fa fa-envelope-o"></i></a>
			</div>
			<h1>gamelab</h1>
		</header>
		<article>
			<p>
				Welcome to the <span class="nm">gamelab</span>, a new web application for online (mobile and desktop) game
				theory experimentation.
				<span class="nm">Gamelab</span> allows experimenters to configure two-player normal-form games for time-based
				play by a pool of participants. 
				Participants accumulate tickets via their payoffs against the average play.
				At the end of the experiment, their tickets are used in a lottery drawing to select winners.
			</p>
			<p>
				<span class="nm">Gamelab</span> was developed for <a href="#">J&ouml;rgen Weibull</a> with financial support from the
				<a href="#">Knut and Alice Wallenberg Research Foundation</a>.  The project design was guided by <a
					href="#">Eskil Forsell</a> and implemented by <a href="#">Kristaps Dzonsons</a>.
			</p>
			<section id="moreinfo">
				<p>
					We're not releasing the <span class="nm">gamelab</span> sources to the public yet&mdash;it's just not
					quite there yet, though well on its way.
					If you're interested in teaming up, contact J&ouml;rgen, Kristaps, or Eskil.
					The software ships as ISO C source code, compiling and installing on any modern UNIX systems (tested on
					modern Mac OS X, Linux, and OpenBSD).
					It requires <a href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi</a>, <a
						href="https://www.sqlite.org/">SQLite</a>, and <a
						href="http://curl.haxx.se/libcurl/">libcurl</a> to compile and run.
					For installation details, the source contains a comprehensive README file.
					In the spirit of academic sharing, it is open source <a rel="license"
						href="http://cvsweb.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/cvsweb/src/share/misc/license.template?rev=HEAD">ISC</a>
					licensed, though we kindly suggest that experimenters cite our work.
				</p>
			</section>
		</article>
		<footer>
			<div>
				&copy; 2015, <a href="http://www.kcons.eu"><i>k</i>-Consulting</a>
			</div>
		</footer>
	</body>
</html>
