<!DOCTYPE html>
<html>
	<head>
		<meta name="viewport" content="initial-scale=1.0, user-scalable=no" />
		<meta charset="utf-8" /> 
		<title>gamelab quickstart</title>
		<link rel="stylesheet" href="https://maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.4.0/css/font-awesome.min.css" />
		<link rel="stylesheet" href="https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Alegreya+Sans:300,300italic" />
		<link rel="stylesheet" href="manual.css" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<header>
			<a href="index.html"><img src="logo.png" alt="Gamelab Logo" /></a>
			<h1><a href="index.html">gamelab</a></h1>
		</header>
		<nav>
			<div><span class="bigview">Version</span> @VERSION@</div>
			<div>
				<a title="Contact" href="mailto:kristaps@kcons.eu">
					<span class="bigview">Contact</span>
					<i class="fa fa-envelope-o"></i>
				</a>
			</div>
			<span>
				<a title="Source Code" href="snapshots">
					<span class="bigview">Download</span>
					<i class="fa fa-cloud-download"></i>
				</a>
			</span>
			<span>
				<a title="GitHub" href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/gamelab">
					<span class="bigview">GitHub</span>
					<i class="fa fa-github"></i>
				</a>
			</span>
			<div>
				<a title="BibTeX Citation" href="gamelab.bib">
					<span class="bigview">Cite</span>
					<i class="fa fa-bookmark"></i>
				</a>
			</div>
		</nav>
		<article>
			<p>
				This document is a brief introduction to deploying <span class="nm">gamelab</span> experiments.
				It assumes you're using <a href="http://gametheorylab.org">gametheorylab.org</a>, which offers experiment
				hosting.
				Start by logging into your experimenter account: the site administrator will have given it to you.
			</p>
			<ol>
				<li>
					<h3>Set your e-mail server.</h3>
					<p>
						Click the <q>E-Mail Server</q> dropdown pane and follow the instructions.
						This is the same configuration you use for your personal e-mail: it lets <span
							class="nm">gamelab</span> send e-mails in your name.
					</p>
				</li>
				<li>
					<h3>Add your games.</h3>
					<p>
						Click the <q>Games</q> and enter your rationally-valued payoffs.
						Include as many actions as you wish; however, more than four or five will clutter mobile
						participants' screens.
					</p>
				</li>
				<li>
					<h3>Add your participants.</h3>
					<p>
						If you want pre-assigned participants, enter their e-mail addresses in the <q>Participants</q>
						input field.
						They will be e-mailed when the experiment begins.
						If you want to run with an unknown number of participants (say, in a laboratory or a seminar),
						choose the <q>Captive</q> option.
						These players are never e-mailed.
						If you want participants to continually be able to join the experiment after it begins, tick the
						<q>Preserve modes</q> box.
					</p>
				</li>
				<li>
					<h3>Determine a running time.</h3>
					<p>
						Open the <q>Experiment Parameters</q> tab and start with your running time.
						You'll need to set a start date and time (in GMT), the maximum time for each round, and the
						number of rounds.
						A good rule of thumb is proximity: if all of your players are close by and focussed (say,
						in a laboratory or classroom), experiments usually progress rapidly.
						As you fan out into e-mailed participants, they'll go more slowly to accomodate for diverse
						schedules.
						It's generally best to set an overly-high number of rounds, then cut off the experiment if it
						exceeds the maximum time you've alloted for it.
						You may want to bring down the <q>percentage-play</q> (when the round automatically advances
						given the number of participants in each player role) as your participant pool grows, else lazy
						participants will drag down your game!
					</p>
				</li>
				<li>
					<h3>Winnings.</h3>
					<p>
						By default, <span class="nm">gamelab</span> uses a lottery to reward participants.
						If you don't want a lottery, then select <q>Advanced Options</q>, set the instructions to <q>No
							Lottery</q>, then tick the <q>Do not show lottery</q> button.
						You can then reward players yourself, or don't reward them at all.
					</p>
				</li>
			</ol>
			<p>
				That's it!
				Hit the <q>Start Experiment</q> button and you're on your way.
				If you want to finish your experiment prior to the full number of rounds, just select the <q>Advance to Last
					Round</q> button in the experiment control at any time.
				This will safely end your experiment, though some participants may be unhappy that they haven't had a chance to
				play through!
			</p>
		</article>
		<footer>
			<div>
				&copy; 2015, 2016, <a href="http://www.kcons.eu"><i>k</i>-Consulting</a>
			</div>
			<div>
				Powered by <a href="https://kristaps.bsd.lv/sblg">sblg</a> on <a href="http://www.openbsd.org">OpenBSD</a>
			</div>
		</footer>
	</body>
</html>
